<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://salvium.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://salvium.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-08T12:58:39+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Salvium Protocol Blog</title><subtitle>Official blog of Salvium Protocol - Latest news and updates</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Privacy Coins and Regulation: Understanding the Challenge</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/29/privacy-coins-and-regulation-understanding-the-challenge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Privacy Coins and Regulation: Understanding the Challenge" /><published>2025-04-29T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/29/privacy-coins-and-regulation-understanding-the-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/29/privacy-coins-and-regulation-understanding-the-challenge/"><![CDATA[<p>In our previous post, we outlined Salvium’s journey so far and our vision for the future. Today, we’ll dive deeper into the specific challenges that privacy-focused cryptocurrencies face in today’s regulatory environment, particularly in Europe under the Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulation.</p>

<h2 id="privacy-coins-valuable-technology-under-pressure">Privacy Coins: Valuable Technology Under Pressure</h2>

<p>Privacy coins emerged as a response to one of cryptocurrency’s fundamental contradictions: blockchain transactions are pseudonymous, not anonymous. Without privacy enhancements, every transaction is permanently visible on public ledgers, creating significant concerns for personal and financial privacy.</p>

<p>Projects like Monero, Zcash, and Salvium address this by implementing cryptographic techniques that shield transaction details while maintaining the integrity of the blockchain. These innovations preserve the financial privacy that most of us take for granted in traditional banking—where our transactions aren’t publicly broadcast for anyone to analyze.</p>

<p>However, these same privacy features have made regulators concerned about potential misuse, leading to increasingly stringent oversight.</p>

<h2 id="the-european-regulatory-landscape">The European Regulatory Landscape</h2>

<p>The European Union’s MiCA framework represents the most comprehensive regulatory approach to cryptocurrencies to date. While MiCA doesn’t explicitly ban privacy coins, it creates conditions that make them extremely difficult to operate within regulated markets:</p>

<h3 id="the-central-exchange-cex-dilemma">The Central Exchange (CEX) Dilemma</h3>

<p>MiCA requires that crypto service providers, including exchanges, ensure all assets they list comply with specific transparency requirements. For privacy coins, this has led to a wave of delistings across European exchanges:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Binance removed privacy coins like Monero and Zcash from platforms in France, Italy, Poland, and Spain</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Kraken subsequently delisted these assets in Ireland and Belgium</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>OKX and other major exchanges have followed similar patterns</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>This trend has significantly reduced the accessibility of privacy coins for European users, pushing transactions to less regulated platforms or peer-to-peer exchanges.</p>

<h3 id="the-key-regulatory-requirements">The Key Regulatory Requirements</h3>

<p>Looking deeper, several specific MiCA provisions create conflicts with traditional privacy coin implementation:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Travel Rule: Transactions over certain thresholds must include identifiable information about both sender and receiver</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>AML and KYC Requirements: Service providers must track and report transactions to comply with anti-money laundering laws</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Transparency Obligations: Detailed records of crypto activities must be maintained</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ban on Anonymous Features: Crypto assets with “built-in anonymization” must allow holders to be identified by crypto service providers</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>For most privacy coins, these requirements present a fundamental contradiction to their core design principles.</p>

<h2 id="the-privacy-paradox">The Privacy Paradox</h2>

<p>This brings us to what we call the “Privacy Paradox”—a situation where:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Users and businesses need financial privacy for legitimate purposes</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Privacy technologies exist that can provide this protection</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Regulatory concerns about misuse limit access to these technologies through regulated channels</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>As a result, privacy becomes accessible only to those willing to operate outside regulated systems</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>This paradox creates a significant divide between the potential benefits of privacy technology and its actual accessibility in daily life. It also means that legitimate businesses and individuals seeking financial privacy are unable to access compliant solutions.</p>

<h2 id="mica-doesnt-ban-privacyit-demands-accountability">MiCA Doesn’t Ban Privacy—It Demands Accountability</h2>

<p>A critical insight that guides Salvium’s approach is that MiCA doesn’t actually ban privacy. Rather, it demands accountability and mechanisms for identifying users when legally required. This distinction creates an opportunity for innovative solutions that can satisfy both needs:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Selective Disclosure: Enabling users to reveal transaction information to authorized parties without compromising global privacy</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Return Functionality: Allowing two-way private transactions with accountability mechanisms</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>View Access: Providing transparency options for compliance without exposing sensitive information to everyone</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="the-technical-challenges">The Technical Challenges</h2>

<p>Creating a system that satisfies both privacy and compliance requirements presents substantial technical challenges:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Cryptographic Complexity: Designing systems that can selectively reveal information while maintaining privacy</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>User Experience: Making compliance mechanisms intuitive and minimally intrusive</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Security: Ensuring that compliance features don’t introduce new vulnerabilities</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Protocol Design: Creating future-proof systems that remain secure even as technologies like quantum computing advance</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>To these technical challenges, we can add the need for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Scalability without compromising privacy</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Forward secrecy to protect past transactions even if keys are compromised</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Protection against emerging threats and analytical techniques</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="beyond-regulation-user-experience-challenges">Beyond Regulation: User Experience Challenges</h2>

<p>While regulatory concerns often dominate discussions around privacy coins, they aren’t the only challenges these technologies face. Significant user experience issues have also limited adoption:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>One-Way Privacy: Most privacy coins excel at sending funds privately but struggle with return payments</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Refund Problems: Merchants cannot easily issue refunds without additional information</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Limited Commercial Applications: Privacy features often come at the cost of functionality needed for everyday commerce</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Verification Difficulties: Proving payment history for accounting or tax purposes becomes complicated</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>These practical limitations have restricted privacy coins to narrow use cases rather than enabling them to serve as comprehensive financial privacy solutions.</p>

<h2 id="the-opportunity-compliance-without-compromise">The Opportunity: Compliance Without Compromise</h2>

<p>The challenges facing privacy coins create a clear opportunity: developing technology that maintains essential privacy while meeting regulatory requirements. This goal—creating compliant privacy—is precisely what Salvium is working to achieve.</p>

<p>In our next post, we’ll explore how Salvium’s approach addresses these challenges through SPARC and other innovations, creating a pathway for privacy coins to operate within regulatory frameworks while preserving their essential functions.</p>

<p>The future of privacy coins depends not on resisting regulation, but on innovating within it—maintaining core privacy values while acknowledging legitimate oversight needs. This balanced approach is what will ultimately bring privacy technology into the mainstream, where its benefits can be widely accessible.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Education" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As privacy coins face increasing regulatory pressure, particularly under MiCA, we explore the challenges and opportunities in creating compliant privacy solutions.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/privacy-regulation.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/privacy-regulation.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Clear Path Forward</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/07/a-path-forward/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Clear Path Forward" /><published>2025-04-07T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-07T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/07/a-path-forward</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/04/07/a-path-forward/"><![CDATA[<p>As we look back on the journey so far and ahead to what’s coming, it’s evident that Salvium has reached a pivotal moment. After weathering challenges and making significant technical breakthroughs, we have clarity on both our direction and purpose. This post marks the first in a series where we’ll explore the problems we’re solving, the innovative solutions we’re implementing, and our vision for the future of privacy in cryptocurrency.</p>

<h2 id="where-we-stand-today-salvium-zero">Where We Stand Today: Salvium Zero</h2>

<p>Our current implementation, Salvium Zero, has proven the core concepts that make our approach unique. As a proof of concept, it successfully demonstrated:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROTOCOL/Asynchronous%20Transactions%20%28AT%29/">Asynchronous transactions</a></strong>: Enabling more complex operations like yield payouts</li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROTOCOL/Protocol_tx/">Protocol TX</a></strong>: A supplementary block-level transaction mechanism for minting new coins</li>
  <li><strong>Return address scheme</strong>: A mechanism allowing recipients to return funds to senders without knowing their address</li>
</ul>

<p>While these innovations set the groundwork for our vision, we recognized limitations in fully meeting regulatory requirements, particularly regarding anti-money laundering (AML) compliance and the European Union’s Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulations.</p>

<h2 id="where-were-going-salvium-one">Where We’re Going: Salvium One</h2>

<p>Salvium One represents a significant evolution, taking the foundation of Salvium Zero and extending it to achieve full regulatory compliance without compromising privacy. The key innovation driving this advancement is <strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/sparc">SPARC</a></strong> (Spend Proof and Anonymized Returns for <a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/carrot">CARROT</a>), which combines:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/sparc/#anonymized-returns">Enhanced return payments</a></strong>: Maintaining privacy while enabling bidirectional transactions</li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/sparc/#spend-authority-proof">Spend authority proofs</a></strong>: Preventing potential money laundering by verifying wallet control</li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/carrot/#full-view-only-wallets">View-only wallet tier</a></strong>: Enabling compliant transaction history reporting without sharing private spend keys</li>
</ul>

<p>This combination of features uniquely positions Salvium among privacy-focused cryptocurrencies. While projects like Monero excel at privacy, they face increasing regulatory challenges and exchange delistings. Salvium’s approach creates a path for privacy coins to operate within regulatory frameworks while preserving their essential privacy features.</p>

<h2 id="the-road-ahead">The Road Ahead</h2>

<p>Our roadmap is ambitious but clear:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Salvium One</strong>: Implementing SPARC to achieve full MiCA compliance and enable CEX listings</li>
  <li><strong>Technical documentation</strong>: Releasing the Salvium One white paper</li>
  <li><strong>Salvium Two</strong>: Laying groundwork for private smart contracts and advancements in scalability</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="engaging-with-our-progress">Engaging With Our Progress</h2>

<p>In upcoming posts, we’ll dive deeper into:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The specific regulatory challenges facing privacy coins and how Salvium addresses them.</li>
  <li>The technical details of <a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/sparc/">SPARC</a> and how it extends the <a href="https://docs.salvium.io/THE%20PROJECT/carrot/">CARROT protocol</a>.</li>
  <li>The mathematics behind our solutions and formal security proofs.</li>
</ul>

<p>We invite the community to engage with these discussions as we build a privacy-focused cryptocurrency that’s both regulatory compliant and technically advanced.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of Salvium's journey, the innovations introduced in Salvium Zero, and the roadmap toward regulatory-compliant privacy in Salvium One.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/a-clear-path.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/a-clear-path.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Audit Completion and Supply Update</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/03/12/audit-completion-supply-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Audit Completion and Supply Update" /><published>2025-03-12T14:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T14:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2025/03/12/audit-completion-supply-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/03/12/audit-completion-supply-update/"><![CDATA[<p>We’re pleased to announce the successful completion of Salvium’s comprehensive supply audit. This audit became necessary after a security incident allowed unauthorized coin minting. For detailed information, please visit: <a href="https://salvium.io/salvium-knowledge-base/salvium-supply-audit/">Salvium Knowledge Base - Supply Audit</a>.</p>

<p>The audit has been thorough and extensive. We deeply appreciate the community’s support throughout this process. With the audit now finalized, we can fully redirect our focus to Salvium One development, accelerating the project into its next phase.</p>

<h3 id="audit-results-and-emission-impact">Audit Results and Emission Impact</h3>

<p>As anticipated, the audit confirmed that unauthorized coins were sold via exchanges. This resulted in approximately 9,459,087 SAL entering circulation ahead of schedule. These coins are now held by innocent purchasers who acquired them without knowledge of their origin.</p>

<p>Most importantly, we have verified that the unauthorized actor no longer possesses any valid coins from the incident. While they attempted to pass 382,600 coins through the audit, these were successfully blacklisted in a hard fork before the funds could be unlocked.</p>

<p>The premature circulation of these coins will not affect the initial maximum supply of 184.4 million SAL. Rather, it has accelerated our emission schedule, meaning the network will reach the planned total emission sooner than originally anticipated. For this reason, “inflation” is not precisely accurate—this represents an acceleration of planned emission rather than an increase to the total supply.</p>

<h3 id="detailed-supply-breakdown-height-179201">Detailed Supply Breakdown (height 179201)</h3>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Description</th>
      <th>Amount</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Total in mining block rewards</td>
      <td>42,501,726</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total in staking rewards (including burnt)</td>
      <td>5,100,431</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total supply</td>
      <td>47,602,157</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total audited</td>
      <td>47,043,844</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total blacklisted</td>
      <td>382,600</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total SAL1 issued through audit</td>
      <td>46,661,244</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Un-audited Treasury SAL</td>
      <td>10,400,000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Accelerated emission (SAL1 issued + treasury - supply)</td>
      <td>9,459,087</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h3 id="governance-fund">Governance Fund</h3>

<p>The 10.4 million SAL from the governance vault that couldn’t be audited (due to being locked) remain in SAL, which is no longer usable. Upon the launch of Salvium One (anticipated in Q2 2025), we plan to implement a consensus-based mechanism to access these coins. Details of this mechanism will be provided at a later date.</p>

<p>The new SAL1 will continue to follow the locking schedule as defined in the lite paper. With the primary audit complete, we can confidently move forward with preparing a detailed treasury report. Despite the temporary inaccessibility of the locked 10.4 million SAL, the project maintains sufficient unlocked funds to fully implement all planned initiatives.</p>

<h3 id="mitigation-strategy">Mitigation Strategy</h3>

<p>The community has explored various strategies to address the accelerated emission, including burning a portion of the governance vault funds. However, given market volatility and uncertainty, it would be imprudent to burn governance funds at this stage, as we cannot precisely predict the capital required for the project’s path to self-sustainability.</p>

<p>It’s worth noting that due to this accelerated emission event, the pre-mine now represents a smaller percentage of the overall circulating supply. All relevant documentation will be updated to reflect these changes.</p>

<p>We sincerely appreciate the community’s patience and continued trust as we implement these critical improvements to secure Salvium’s long-term integrity and sustainability.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Important update on our recent audit completion and current supply status of Salvium.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/audit-complete.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/audit-complete.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Audit 0.8.0</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/09/audit-080/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Audit 0.8.0" /><published>2025-01-09T16:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-09T16:05:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/09/audit-080</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/09/audit-080/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-audit-has-started">The audit has started!</h1>

<p>Let’s get the bad news out of the way first. User-submitted transactions are temporarily disabled, but mining and existing yield accrual continues as normal, in preparation for the next phase of the audit.</p>

<p>Now the good news. Working with a world-renowned cryptographic consultancy company supporting us, we are taking a different approach to this audit compared to ideas that have been proposed for other Monero-based coins recently. There will be some short-term compromises on privacy, but we believe that the end result will justify the methods.</p>

<p>The audit will require everyone to perform a once-per-wallet “STAKE” transaction from the CLI wallet. (GUI wallet support for the audit process will possibly be added if the timescales permit.) This “STAKE” transaction will burn all the coins in the wallet, and record how many coins were found. The coins will then accrue yield (like a normal staking transaction in Salvium) for a period of 10 days (not the normal 30 days).</p>

<p>During those 10 days, the contents of the transaction will be analysed by both dedicated cryptographic software and by members of the team to look for anomalies. If nothing is found, then at the end of the 10 days the coins (including the earned yield) will be paid out, and you will be free to perform transactions with the new coins as normal.</p>

<p>If any anomalies are detected with the transaction, it will be flagged publicly, and the team will ask individuals to explain the anomaly privately to the team, before the coins are returned. If no individual comes forward to explain the anomaly, the coins will not be returned.</p>

<h2 id="current-status">Current status:</h2>

<ul>
  <li>A hard fork v5 has been implemented at block height 136,100</li>
  <li>Wallets should be updated to v0.8.0. <a href="https://salvium.io/downloads/"><strong>CLI Binaries are available here</strong></a>. Desktop wallets will be available soon.</li>
  <li>All TRANSFER, STAKE, BURN, and RETURN_PAYMENT transactions are now disabled</li>
  <li>The chain continues to run and mining continues</li>
  <li>Yield payments on existing stakes will also continue to be processed normally</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-audit-process">The Audit Process</h2>

<p>To ensure the accuracy of the Salvium Supply figures, we will conduct a second fork as soon as possible that will enforce a comprehensive supply audit. This will be done using a modified version of the existing staking functionality. It will be updated so that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>All SAL holders are required to participate in a compulsory staking process.</li>
  <li>A reduced 10-day lock period for audit stakes (reduced from 30 days)</li>
  <li>Audit functionality will be enabled - counting and monitoring staked coins.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="blocking-suspicious-transactions">Blocking suspicious transactions</h3>

<p>The steps in the audit process are as follows:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Users will submit a “stake” command from the CLI wallet (GUI wallet support will be added if possible during the audit process)</li>
  <li>The user’s wallet will then construct one or more STAKE transactions that will burn all of their coins using standard “protocol_tx” processes for a period of 10 days. The STAKE transaction(s) will contain special audit data, including:
    <ul>
      <li>The wallet public keys {Ks,Kv}</li>
      <li>Linkage data that proves each input being spent has come from the wallet with the specified public keys.</li>
      <li>Proof that the transaction does not provide any change - i.e. that all coins have been burnt</li>
      <li>The aggregated value in SAL of all of the inputs</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>The STAKE transaction(s) will be rejected if there is any discrepancy between wallet keys, or if any attempt is made to alter the amount of change being generated.</li>
  <li>The valid STAKE transaction(s) will be mined, and then are immutable on-chain, and verifiable by ANY OBSERVER - we are hoping that the community will help us be vigilant and spot potentially suspicious transactions (although we already have a dedicated scanning tool that flags everything we currently consider “suspicious”)</li>
  <li>If any transactions are flagged by the scanning tool, we will notify the community during the first 3 days after they enter the chain (through Discord and Telegram). If the team does not receive adequate proof of ownership for those coins within 4 subsequent days (i.e. within 7 days of submission) the transaction (and potentially also the wallet address) will be blacklisted. Blacklisted transactions will NOT pay out when the STAKE matures after 10 days.</li>
  <li>STAKE transactions that are not blacklisted will pay out in a new asset type “SAL1” upon maturing. SAL1 outputs will be spendable in all normal transaction types, and will be considered as audited.</li>
</ol>

<p>After approximately 30 days (21,600 blocks), the audit process will end. At that time, it will no longer be possible to submit SAL coins in any transaction - only SAL1 will be spendable in any way.</p>

<p>Mining block rewards from blocks after the start of the audit process will pay out in SAL1, not SAL - those coins will already be audited and will not need to be staked. Coins that have already been staked prior to the start of the audit process will be allowed to mature at the normal time, and will also pay out in SAL1, not SAL.</p>

<h2 id="exchange-status">Exchange Status</h2>

<p>All exchanges have been notified and will remain closed until the situation is fully resolved. We are in direct communication with exchange partners about the required steps for re-enabling trading.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details on the completion and findings of the Salvium v0.8.0 audit.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/audit-080.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/audit-080.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding the Potential Inflation Vulnerability – Jan 2025</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/06/potential-inflation-vulnerability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding the Potential Inflation Vulnerability – Jan 2025" /><published>2025-01-06T12:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T12:58:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/06/potential-inflation-vulnerability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2025/01/06/potential-inflation-vulnerability/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>We are now at the stage where we can share further details regarding the recent Salvium 0.7.x hard forks. We know that we have been slow in sharing this information, but it has been important for us to ensure its accuracy.</p>

<p>At the end of December, the core team initiated several hard forks to patch vulnerabilities that had been identified.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, a missing ZK proof created a particular vulnerability that would allow a malicious actor to mint new coins in a way that would not be detected by the chain analysis script. This introduced the risk of a hidden inflation hack, which we are taking very seriously.</p>

<p>The custom chain analysis script that we developed was of no use in the case of this particular exploit.</p>

<p>This document sets out the nature of the vulnerability, along with the ZK proof that was deployed in v0.7.0 to prevent the risk of future exploitation. To ensure confidence in the protocol, we are currently planning an audit to confirm the exact supply.</p>

<h2 id="overview-of-vulnerability">Overview of Vulnerability</h2>

<p>Salvium attempted to incorporate improvements over Monero, the coin on which Salvium was built. One such improvement was a “commitment to a difference,” rather than a “commitment to zero” as used by the Monero system. Monero’s “commitment to zero” approach meant that the commitment masks could not all be chosen independently. Implementing a “commitment to a difference” and providing that commitment in the transaction, allowed all commitment masks for all inputs and outputs in the transaction to be independent of one another.</p>

<p>The “difference commitment” is calculated when generating the input and output commitments as:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pr = Commit(sumPseudoOuts - sumOuts, 0)</code></p>

<p>However, in versions of Salvium before the 0.7.0 update, Salvium did not include proof that the “difference” commitment (denoted ) contained a zero “amount.” This resulted in the described vulnerability, which allowed for the potential creation of coins without leaving detectable evidence on the blockchain.</p>

<h2 id="the-missing-proof">The Missing Proof</h2>

<h3 id="the-required-proof">The Required Proof</h3>

<p>The required proof (that the difference commitment had no amount component, i.e., <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">p</code>) was a straightforward Schnorr-like sigma-protocol, as follows:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Generate a random scalar <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">b</code>.</li>
  <li>Compute <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">r = b · G + 0 · h</code>, where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">G</code> is the generator point and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">h</code> is the zero scalar.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="prover-steps-for-a-commitment-difference-d">Prover Steps (for a commitment difference d):</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Generates a random scalar <em>r</em> (a nonce).</li>
  <li>Generates a commitment to the scalar, i.e. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">R = r · G</code>.</li>
  <li>Computes a commitment to the difference, with zero amount, i.e. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Cd = Commit(d, 0)</code>.</li>
  <li>Calculates a challenge <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">c = Hs(R || Cd)</code>.</li>
  <li>Calculates a response to the challenge <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">z = r + c · d</code>.</li>
  <li>Stores the tuple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">{R, z}</code> and the commitment to the difference <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Cd</code> in the transaction data.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="verifier-steps">Verifier Steps</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Recomputes the challenge from the proof and public data <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">c' = Hs(R || Cd)</code>.</li>
  <li>Recomputes the commitment to the scalar <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">R' = z · G - c · Cd</code>.</li>
  <li>Tests <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">R' ?= R</code> - if they are equal, then the commitment has a zero (0) amount term and is valid.</li>
</ol>

<p>By adding this proof in v0.7.0, Salvium has prevented any future exploitation of this vulnerability.</p>

<h2 id="audit-and-impact">Audit and Impact</h2>

<p>We must accept that the presence of a vulnerability means there is a risk that there has been an inflation hack. Given that Salvium is a private coin with an amount hiding, the only way to truly ascertain the circulating supply is to audit the coins. To that end, Salvium will undergo an audit to confirm the exact supply. For security, specific details of the audit won’t be shared at this stage.</p>

<h2 id="exchanges">Exchanges</h2>

<p>Exchanges were originally closed while we resolved the chain split. This issue has now been addressed, but it is prudent for exchanges to remain closed until the situation is clearer.</p>

<h2 id="acknowledgment-and-commitment">Acknowledgment and Commitment</h2>

<p>We acknowledge the disruption caused by the rapid implementation of hard forks and appreciate the community’s patience. Moving forward, our focus remains on transparency and security. Thank you for your understanding and trust as we navigate this crucial period.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical analysis of the potential inflation vulnerability and our response.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/zx-vulnerability.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/zx-vulnerability.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Salvium’s v0.6 Series - Improved Difficulty Algorithm</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/11/04/v06-series-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Salvium’s v0.6 Series - Improved Difficulty Algorithm" /><published>2024-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2024/11/04/v06-series-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/11/04/v06-series-update/"><![CDATA[<p>As we approach our upcoming network upgrade, we want to explain the journey of our v0.6 series and why these changes were made. Since releasing v0.6.0, community feedback and testing have led to several refinements, culminating in our latest release, v0.6.3.</p>

<h2 id="improved-difficulty-adjustments">Improved Difficulty Adjustments</h2>

<p>A key improvement in this upgrade is our transition to the Linearly Weighted Moving Average (LWMA) difficulty adjustment algorithm. While Salvium continues to use RandomX as its proven Proof of Work algorithm, LWMA changes how we adjust mining difficulty between blocks.</p>

<h4 id="why-this-matters">Why This Matters:</h4>

<ul>
  <li>More stable block times through better difficulty adjustments</li>
  <li>Improved response to hashrate fluctuations</li>
  <li>Better resistance against block timing manipulation</li>
  <li>More predictable and consistent block intervals</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-evolution-of-v06">The Evolution of v0.6</h2>

<p>Our journey to v0.6.3 has been driven by community feedback and real-world testing:</p>

<h4 id="v060-the-foundation">v0.6.0: The Foundation</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Introduced LWMA difficulty adjustments</li>
  <li>Implemented new consensus rules (HF1)</li>
  <li>Established base protocol improvements</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="v601-v602-refinement">v6.0.1-v6.0.2: Refinement</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Enhanced wallet performance</li>
  <li>Improved transaction handling</li>
  <li>Fixed minor operational issues</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="v063-the-complete-package">v0.6.3: The Complete Package</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Increased transaction input limit from 18 to 120+</li>
  <li>Enhanced exchange integration capabilities</li>
  <li>Resolved return_payment function issues</li>
  <li>Final optimizations for upcoming Hard Fork 2</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="impact-for-different-users">Impact for Different Users</h2>

<h4 id="for-miners">For Miners</h4>

<p>While RandomX remains unchanged as our mining algorithm, the new difficulty adjustment system will provide more consistent block times and better handling of network hashrate changes. This means more predictable mining conditions for all participants.</p>

<h4 id="for-exchanges">For Exchanges</h4>

<p>The increased transaction input limit (now 120+) directly addresses feedback from exchanges, allowing for more efficient handling of withdrawals and better overall integration.</p>

<h4 id="for-regular-users">For Regular Users</h4>

<p>You’ll experience more reliable transactions, better wallet performance, and more consistent block times. The improvements in difficulty adjustments mean more predictable transaction confirmation times.</p>

<h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2>

<p>These updates fine-tune Salvium’s existing strengths. The improved difficulty adjustments, enhanced transaction capabilities, and overall stability improvements position us well for the upcoming Hard Fork 2 and beyond.</p>

<h4 id="action-required">Action Required</h4>

<h1 id="all-users-must-upgrade-to-v063-before-block-height-89800-expected-tuesday-november-5th-gmt-this-upgrade-is-mandatory-to-maintain-network-consensus-download-the-latest-version-githubcomsalviumsalviumreleasestagv063-were-grateful-for-our-communitys-patience-and-feedback-throughout-this-process-these-improvements-reflect-our-commitment-to-building-a-robust-fair-and-efficient-privacy-focused-blockchain-the-salvium-core-team">All users must upgrade to v0.6.3 before block height 89,800 (expected Tuesday, November 5th, GMT). This upgrade is mandatory to maintain network consensus. Download the latest version: <a href="https://github.com/salvium/salvium/releases/tag/v0.6.3">github.com/salvium/salvium/releases/tag/v0.6.3</a> We’re grateful for our community’s patience and feedback throughout this process. These improvements reflect our commitment to building a robust, fair, and efficient privacy-focused blockchain. <em>The Salvium Core Team</em></h1>

<p>The v0.6 series brings significant improvements to Salvium’s difficulty adjustment algorithm, enhancing network stability and mining efficiency. This update represents a major step forward in our ongoing commitment to network optimization and security.</p>

<p>Our new difficulty algorithm introduces faster adjustment responses to hash rate changes, enhanced stability against time-warp attacks, and more precise difficulty targeting. These improvements ensure a more reliable and efficient mining experience for all participants.</p>

<p>The updated algorithm uses a rolling window of block times and implements weighted averaging that prioritizes recent blocks while considering historical data. We’ve also added guard rails to prevent extreme difficulty swings, making the network more stable and predictable.</p>

<p>These improvements translate into a more stable mining experience with better rewards distribution. Miners will see more consistent block times, improved profitability through predictable mining rewards, and reduced orphan rates thanks to better block time consistency.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing key improvements in Salvium v0.6, featuring a new difficulty adjustment algorithm for better network stability.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/difficulty-algo.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/difficulty-algo.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Club Dinero AMA</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/18/club-dinero-ama/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Club Dinero AMA" /><published>2024-09-18T07:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T07:51:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/18/club-dinero-ama</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/18/club-dinero-ama/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="1-what-inspired-the-creation-of-salvium-and-how-does-it-differ-from-other-privacy-focused-defi-projects">1. What inspired the creation of Salvium, and how does it differ from other privacy-focused DeFi projects?</h2>

<p>Salvium’s origins can be traced to insights gained at MoneroKon 2019, particularly from Pedro Moreno-Sánchez’s presentation on enabling payment channels in Monero. This sparked our interest in exploring the balance between privacy, scalability, and functionality in cryptocurrencies. Initially, we called the project “Fulmo,” meaning “lightning” in Esperanto, but as we delved deeper into conditional payments and asynchronous transactions, we realized we were creating something much more powerful – an approach that enabled smart contracts while maintaining privacy. That’s when Salvium was born.</p>

<p>What sets Salvium apart is our unique approach to integrating privacy with DeFi. Our protocol_tx mechanism allows for more sophisticated transaction types than traditional privacy coins. We’ve developed features like Transactional Imbalances and Asynchronous Transactions that enable complex DeFi operations within a privacy-preserving framework. In addition, without compromising privacy, we have built-in compliance features like refundable transactions and selective disclosure. This means that we can meet new Mica rules for listing on centralized exchanges.</p>

<h2 id="2-how-is-salvium-striking-a-balance-between-maintaining-user-privacy-and-adhering-to-regulations-without-compromising-its-privacy-features">2. How is Salvium striking a balance between maintaining user privacy and adhering to regulations, without compromising its privacy features?</h2>

<p>The first thing to understand is that we haven’t compromised any of Monero’s native privacy features. We have enhanced them. The compliance features don’t interfere with privacy, they provide optional features on top, so there is no compromise with privacy.</p>

<p>To achieve compliance, we have added refundable transactions that allow exchanges to return funds, without compromising the privacy of the original sender. We are also developing a view key mechanism using a dual-key system that enables authorized entities to view transaction history and balances without the ability to spend funds or link transactions to external identities. But it’s the holder who chooses who to authorize. And which wallet to authorize. This approach allows us to operate in regulated environments while still providing robust privacy for most users and transactions.</p>

<h2 id="3-how-does-salvium-fit-into-the-broader-defi-ecosystem-what-kind-of-defi-applications-do-you-envision-being-built-on-salvium">3. How does Salvium fit into the broader DeFi ecosystem? What kind of DeFi applications do you envision being built on Salvium?</h2>

<p>We see Salvium as a foundational layer for privacy-preserving DeFi applications. Our goal is to enable complex financial operations with built-in privacy features, something that’s unique in the current DeFi landscape.</p>

<p>As for the types of DeFi applications we envision, there’s a wide range. We’re excited about the potential for private AMM DEXes that could leverage our Asynchronous Transactions to enable swaps without revealing trade sizes or user identities. We also see great potential for privacy-preserving lending protocols, using our Transactional Imbalances to manage collateralization and liquidations privately.</p>

<p>Other possibilities include anonymous yield farming, private options and derivatives, confidential stablecoins, and even privacy-focused prediction markets. Salvium could support anonymous governance systems, enabling private voting for DAO-like structures. The key advantage here is that all these applications would benefit from Salvium’s native privacy features, compliance capabilities, and advanced transaction types. This allows for services that are challenging or impossible to implement on other platforms while maintaining strong privacy guarantees.</p>

<h2 id="4-are-there-partnerships-or-integrations-planned-with-other-defi-platforms-or-projects">4. Are there partnerships or integrations planned with other DeFi platforms or projects?</h2>

<p>Partnerships and integrations will be a core part of our growth strategy. Our current focus is to meet all the requirements for listing on centralized exchanges in the EU. The bulk of the development for this has been done, but the ability to view the wallet needs to be completed. This will unlock our first major CEX.</p>

<p>We are constantly having discussions around the potential of DeFi - but the real conversations won’t take shape until after the view wallet work is complete.</p>

<h2 id="5-what-are-the-major-advantages-of-using-salvium-for-defi-protocols-compared-to-other-platforms-particularly-in-terms-of-privacy">5. What are the major advantages of using Salvium for DeFi protocols compared to other platforms, particularly in terms of privacy?</h2>

<p>Yes, privacy is the feature that differentiates us in DeFi. And nobody shouldn’t underestimate how seriously we take this, we are still building Privacy features now, and following developments in the Monero community very closely.</p>

<p>But our biggest advantage is that we embrace 3 big concepts in crypto. Privacy, compliance and DeFi. We published a Venn diagram recently that explains our unique position in crypto. Coins that comply with crypto regulations will have far greater reach - so we believe compliant privacy will be dominant in the future. We are tipped to become one of the first compliant, private defi projects.</p>

<h2 id="6-what-are-the-key-milestones-on-the-salvium-roadmap-and-what-should-we-expect-from-the-upcoming-06-release">6. What are the key milestones on the Salvium roadmap, and what should we expect from the upcoming 0.6 release?</h2>

<p>0.6 is a relatively minor update. The next significant milestone is Salvium 1.0 - as this will be when we meet the Mica Regulations. The return address is already live, but we will have “exchange mode” - which is where an enhanced view key option will give users options to share wallet details with exchanges.</p>

<p>This will be included in Salvium 1.0 which will enable our first listing on a regulated CEX. This is a huge milestone as it will demonstrate the power of compliant privacy. Devs are working on the maths now, we plan to conduct another audit before writing the code and intend to launch it in the new year.</p>

<h2 id="7-can-you-elaborate-on-the-hard-fork-thats-part-of-the-06-release-what-changes-or-improvements-can-users-expect">7. Can you elaborate on the hard fork that’s part of the 0.6 release? What changes or improvements can users expect?</h2>

<p>Yes, it will be a hard fork that enables support for multiple outputs, it will make things easier for the pool operators. However, the main event will be 1.0 - when full compliance becomes a reality. But we do expect wallets to be updated before then. This will enable multi-sig, required by some bigger exchanges. And hopefully a Mac OS and even an Android GUI.</p>

<h2 id="8-are-there-plans-to-expand-salviums-use-cases-beyond-privacy-focused-defi">8. Are there plans to expand Salvium’s use cases beyond privacy-focused DeFi?</h2>

<p>Private DeFi is our core focus, which in itself is incredibly broad. This alone could keep us busy for decades. That said, we are very aware of the applications for this kind of privacy technology outside of finance.</p>

<p>We have discussed voting systems. Our anonymous yet verifiable transaction structure could be used to create secure, private voting mechanisms - which I hope will form a core part of Salvium’s governance going forward. Our encryption and identity protection features have potential applications in secure, private communication platforms.</p>

<p>There are also applications in supply-chain management, where our verifiable transaction system could be used for tracking goods while maintaining business confidentiality. Healthcare data management is likely to leverage blockchain technology to handle sensitive medical data. Gaming and digital collectibles too, where we could create platforms for tradeable digital assets with privacy features.</p>

<p>We’ve even considered how our cryptographic primitives could be used in privacy-preserving machine learning systems and confidential IoT data management. That said, DeFi will be our focus. Expansion must align with our core competencies and not dilute our primary focus. But as privacy becomes increasingly important across various sectors, we believe Salvium’s technology could find numerous applications beyond DeFi. And as a decentralized and open source project, we’d encourage anyone with an interest in any of these areas to take the initiative and run with it.</p>

<h2 id="9-weve-heard-discussions-about-a-wrapped-sal-wsal-how-will-this-function-and-will-there-be-a-bridge-for-seamless-onboarding-from-ethereum-back-to-native-sal-additionally-how-will-this-benefit-salvium-in-the-long-term">9. We’ve heard discussions about a wrapped SAL (wSAL). How will this function, and will there be a bridge for seamless onboarding from Ethereum back to native SAL? Additionally, how will this benefit Salvium in the long term?</h2>

<p>The wrapped SAL (wSAL) is an important initiative for expanding Salvium’s ecosystem and improving interoperability. Essentially, wSAL will be an ERC-20 token on Ethereum that represents native SAL at a 1:1 ratio. We want to develop a decentralized bridge to facilitate the wrapping and unwrapping process. Users will be able to lock native SAL and mint an equivalent amount of wSAL, or burn wSAL to release native SAL.</p>

<p>In terms of long-term benefits, there are several key advantages. First, wSAL can be traded on Ethereum DEXes, which could potentially increase overall liquidity for SAL. It also means users can interact with SAL through familiar Ethereum wallets and interfaces, broadening our accessibility.</p>

<p>Perhaps most excitingly, wSAL can be used in Ethereum’s vast DeFi ecosystem, which significantly expands the use cases for SAL. This also lays the groundwork for future cross-chain applications and interoperability. Listing on Ethereum-based DEXes could increase visibility for Salvium and attract new users to our ecosystem. We’re really seeing this as a way to position Salvium as a bridge between privacy-focused and mainstream blockchain ecosystems.</p>

<h2 id="10-monero-is-planning-to-implement-fcmp-does-salvium-have-any-plans-to-adopt-this-technology-if-so-how-could-salvium-potentially-benefit-from-its-implementation-in-the-future">10. Monero is planning to implement FCMP++. Does Salvium have any plans to adopt this technology? If so, how could Salvium potentially benefit from its implementation in the future?</h2>

<p>We are in discussions with Kayaba regarding the early adoption of certain aspects of the FCMP++ implementation into Salvium. In particular, the FCMP++ solution for output view keys appears to be a perfect fit for Salvium’s need to allow authorized viewing of a wallet’s transaction history. The most likely scenario is that FCMP++ will have a phased adoption into Salvium, and there is a good chance this will happen ahead of its’ deployment within Monero.</p>

<h2 id="11-are-there-any-plans-to-introduce-mobile-or-hardware-wallets-for-salvium-weve-heard-about-potential-integration-with-cake-wallet-can-you-provide-an-update-on-how-thats-progressing-and-whether-its-likely-to-happen-in-the-near-future">11. Are there any plans to introduce mobile or hardware wallets for Salvium? We’ve heard about potential integration with Cake Wallet, can you provide an update on how that’s progressing and whether it’s likely to happen in the near future?</h2>

<p>We’ve recently launched a desktop GUI wallet for Windows and Linux. It’s built on a re-skinned fork of the Monero GUI wallet with additional staking functionality. Users can gain 20% of the block reward in private with a few clicks in the wallet. This has given us a Windows and Linux wallet - and we expect Mac OS version soon - and hopefully an Android version too.</p>

<p>Cake Wallet would be fantastic. We have reached out to the Cake Wallet team and are very willing to put in the development work to make this happen. Nothing has been confirmed yet. On the hardware wallet front, we haven’t progressed this yet, but it’s definitely on the wish list.</p>

<p>Our goal is to ensure that Salvium users have a range of secure, user-friendly wallet options that cater to different needs and preferences. We recognise that expanding our wallet ecosystem is crucial for wider adoption and accessibility of Salvium.</p>

<h2 id="12-are-there-any-plans-for-salvium-to-be-integrated-with-serai-dex-in-the-future">12. Are there any plans for Salvium to be integrated with Serai Dex in the future?</h2>

<p>It’s certainly on our wish list! Ultimately it is down to Serai to decide what coins to include in their DEX, but we do believe that a regulatory-compliant privacy coin has a place in a leading-edge privacy project like Serai.</p>

<h2 id="13-where-do-you-see-salvium-and-its-ecosystem-in-the-next-24-months">13. Where do you see Salvium and its ecosystem in the next 24 months?</h2>

<p>With a clear and straightforward plan, we aim to become the go-to private and compliant blockchain for Layer-2 decentralized applications (dApps) - this can be achieved within 24 months. This will allow us to be listed on regulated exchanges, setting us apart from most other privacy coins.</p>

<p>We aim to have a user-friendly experience that allows developers to use Salvium as a base coin in Layer-2 dApps. This introduces a crucial concept: Layer 2 tokens can inherit key properties from the Salvium base layer coin. While the specific features will depend on the chosen implementation, developers will have the flexibility to incorporate compliant privacy into their dApps if desired. This effectively represents the emergence of a new class of tokens, tailored for both privacy and regulatory compliance.</p>

<p>Many privacy-focused projects will struggle with the new regulations. With Salvium’s base coin, teams will be able to develop tokens and Apps that offer both privacy benefits and meet the rules that allow a major CEX listing. This fills a significant gap in crypto.</p>

<p>In parallel, we aim to assemble an exceptional team, a vibrant community, and strategic partners who will help us grow.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Full transcript of our AMA session with the Club Dinero community discussing Salvium's vision and technology.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/ama-club-d.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/optimized/ama-club-d.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Pursuit of Privacy AMA – Highlights &amp;amp; Insights</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/09/privacy-ama/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pursuit of Privacy AMA – Highlights &amp;amp; Insights" /><published>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/09/privacy-ama</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/09/09/privacy-ama/"><![CDATA[<p>On August 20th, the Salvium devs joined the Pursuit of Privacy community for an AMA. Thanks for hosting—it was a great discussion!</p>

<p>In this AMA, we explore Salvium’s origins, its Confidential Transactions, staking model, and key innovations like Asynchronous Transactions (AT) and Transactional Imbalances (TI). We also discuss the team’s funding strategy and how Salvium aims to position itself as a leader in the privacy coin space.</p>

<h2 id="1-to-start-the-ama-can-you-tell-us-the-story-behind-the-salvium-project-and-what-it-aims-to-achieve">1. To start the AMA, can you tell us the story behind the Salvium project, and what it aims to achieve?</h2>

<p>Salvium was originally called Fulmo as a nod to Monero (meaning ‘coin’), Fulmo means ‘lightning’ in Esperanto. The original concept was inspired by a presentation by Pedro Moreno-Sánchez at MoneroKon 2019 on “Dual Outputs: Enabling Payment-Channel Networks in Monero”. You can find it on YouTube. He highlighted the trade-offs between privacy, scalability, and functionality in cryptocurrencies and laid out a proposal using dual outputs to enable payment channels, and a lightning network style layer 2. While working through various ideas to use this extended capability set, and considering what things like conditional payments would enable, a prototype was built for a yield payment system that paid out asynchronously. Only at that point did it become clear that if you can send a transaction at one point in time, and have it do ‘stuff’ at some point in the future, then return it securely and privately—you’ve just built a system capable of running code on the blockchain. So Fulmo became too limiting a name, and Salvium was born.</p>

<h2 id="2-can-you-tell-us-about-each-team-members-background-have-you-worked-on-other-projects-before">2. Can you tell us about each team member’s background? Have you worked on other projects before?</h2>

<p>While we haven’t focused on individual identities, we’re not anonymous. But we are also not seeking exposure. The lead developers are known in the space as Dweab and Neac and are responsible for creating the coloured coin technology used in projects like Haven Protocol. Both are also fully doxxed, and their careers are known. Dweab started as a software engineer and mathematician and then went into high-level corporate roles. Neac has been a software engineer for over 30 years and is also a very accomplished and capable mathematician and cryptographer. Beyond these two individuals, there is a wider team of contributors that have a broad range of skills, including economics, finance, DevOps, technical, and creative.</p>

<h2 id="3-you-have-chosen-to-have-the-project-funds-12-of-max-supply-locked-in-a-contract-with-gradual-release-over-24-months-why-did-you-choose-this-setup-over-other-funding-options-such-as-a-block-tax-premine-or-community-donations">3. You have chosen to have the project funds (12% of max supply) locked in a contract with gradual release over 24 months. Why did you choose this setup over other funding options, such as a block tax, premine, or community donations?</h2>

<p>We chose a 9% premine with a 24-month gradual release because it provides both transparency and financial stability. Another 3% was allocated to early contributors and the founding team, compensating them for nearly a year of development and costs before launch. By releasing 650,000 SAL per month, we have a stable funding source to deliver on our roadmap. We considered alternatives like community donations or ongoing developer fees, but those options either lacked financial stability or posed potential conflicts of interest. The 24-month lock-up also shows our commitment to the project’s long-term vision. In August 2024, we locked one month of unused payments for another two years to demonstrate our long-term commitment. This model allows us to focus on development without short-term market pressures.</p>

<h2 id="4-people-rarely-discuss-the-choices-of-tokenomics-and-project-financing-rewardspremine-over-a-timeline-dont-you-think-your-choice-to-allocate-salviums-project-funding-with-a-token-release-over-24-months-is-risky-given-the-current-market-conditions-it-seems-like-a-short-term-bet-where-a-bull-market-within-the-next-two-years-is-necessary-to-ensure-your-funding-for-the-subsequent-years-the-timing-of-sales-must-be-very-well-chosen-to-avoid-running-out-of-funding-for-future-developments-after-the-first-two-years-what-are-your-thoughts-on-this">4. People rarely discuss the choices of tokenomics and project financing (rewards/premine) over a timeline. Don’t you think your choice to allocate Salvium’s project funding with a token release over 24 months is risky given the current market conditions? It seems like a short-term bet where a bull market within the next two years is necessary to ensure your funding for the subsequent years. The timing of sales must be very well chosen to avoid running out of funding for future developments (after the first two years). What are your thoughts on this?</h2>

<p>The 24-month release was designed to meet Salvium’s initial funding needs while aligning with the community’s interests. We’re aware of the market risks, but we aren’t relying on a bull market. Our strategy includes prudent financial management, a flexible development pace that can adapt to SAL’s value, and the potential for locking additional unused SAL tokens for future use. This is to build real value and generate trust and ongoing interest. Transparency with our community is crucial throughout this process.</p>

<h2 id="5-the-knowledge-base-section-of-your-website-mentions-that-salvium-uses-confidential-transactions-to-mask-transaction-amounts-can-you-explain-in-detail-the-cryptographic-mechanism-used-to-implement-these-confidential-transactions-and-how-it-differs-from-implementations-in-other-blockchains-like-monero-or-zcash-additionally-how-do-you-manage-the-verification-of-transaction-integrity-without-revealing-the-amounts">5. The Knowledge Base section of your website mentions that Salvium uses ‘Confidential Transactions’ to mask transaction amounts. Can you explain in detail the cryptographic mechanism used to implement these confidential transactions, and how it differs from implementations in other blockchains like Monero or Zcash? Additionally, how do you manage the verification of transaction integrity without revealing the amounts?</h2>

<p>Salvium’s Confidential Transactions (CTs) are the same as Monero’s, with the exception that Salvium also provides uniformly random commitment masks for all consumed outputs, as opposed to some consumed outputs as Monero does, creating a reduction in the potential for information leakage.</p>

<h2 id="6-staking-on-salvium-is-based-on-periods-of-approximately-30-days-21600-blocks-with-a-yield-of-20-of-block-rewards-during-the-initial-phase-of-the-project-how-does-the-salvium-protocol-plan-to-adjust-these-staking-rewards-during-the-transition-to-a-fee-based-defi-model-while-maintaining-sufficient-incentives-for-participants">6. Staking on Salvium is based on periods of approximately 30 days (21,600 blocks) with a yield of 20% of block rewards during the initial phase of the project. How does the Salvium protocol plan to adjust these staking rewards during the transition to a fee-based DeFi model, while maintaining sufficient incentives for participants?</h2>

<p>Maintaining network security and participant incentives is a priority. The current 20% share of block rewards for stakers will remain in place as we begin rolling out DeFi features in the future. As DeFi applications grow and generate revenue, we’ll gradually transition from block reward-based staking to a gas/fee distribution model. This transition will be carefully managed, ensuring that stakers continue to receive attractive rewards. We’ll be transparent about any changes and seek community input to strike the right balance, ensuring the economic model remains sustainable as we expand DeFi capabilities.</p>

<h2 id="7-salvium-introduces-anonymous-refundable-transactions-as-a-compliance-feature-can-you-detail-the-cryptographic-process-that-allows-for-an-anonymous-refund-of-a-transaction-while-ensuring-the-exact-amount-is-returned-to-the-correct-sender-how-does-this-mechanism-integrate-with-other-privacy-features-of-salvium-such-as-stealth-addresses-and-ring-signatures">7. Salvium introduces anonymous refundable transactions as a compliance feature. Can you detail the cryptographic process that allows for an anonymous refund of a transaction while ensuring the exact amount is returned to the correct sender? How does this mechanism integrate with other privacy features of Salvium, such as Stealth Addresses and Ring Signatures?</h2>

<p>Our approach builds upon the “Return Address Scheme” originally proposed by Knacc for Monero in 2019, adapting and extending it to meet the specific needs of Salvium’s regulatory compliance goals. We developed the mathematical proof for this in early 2024, and CypherStack audited it just before the launch of Salvium’s mainnet. Salvium’s refundable transactions are an optional feature that integrates privacy with regulatory compliance. When Alice sends a transaction to Bob, she includes an encrypted “return address” (F_ab) in the transaction, which Bob can later use if a refund is needed. This return address is encrypted using a Diffie-Hellman shared secret, ensuring only Bob can decrypt it. If a refund is required, Bob can use this information to create a new transaction without knowing Alice’s actual address. This method preserves privacy by using stealth addresses and ring signatures, maintaining unlinkability and anonymity while enabling refunds. The refund amount is verified using Pedersen commitments and range proofs, ensuring the integrity of the transaction.</p>

<h2 id="8-in-the-knowledge-base-section-it-is-mentioned-that-exchanges-require-the-ability-to-monitor-transactions-in-authorized-wallets-via-a-viewkey-mechanism-can-you-explain-how-this-view-key-mechanism-is-technically-implemented-in-the-salvium-protocol-and-how-it-ensures-both-user-privacy-and-regulatory-compliance-what-security-measures-are-in-place-to-prevent-the-abuse-of-these-view-keys-by-authorized-entities">8. In the Knowledge Base section, it is mentioned that exchanges require the ability to monitor transactions in authorized wallets via a ‘viewkey’ mechanism. Can you explain how this ‘view key’ mechanism is technically implemented in the Salvium protocol, and how it ensures both user privacy and regulatory compliance? What security measures are in place to prevent the abuse of these ‘view keys’ by ‘authorized entities’?</h2>

<p>The view key mechanism is currently being developed. It is being designed as an optional feature to balance privacy with compliance. Salvium will use a dual-key system: a ‘view-balance key’ (k_vb) and a ‘master key’ (k_m). The view-balance key allows authorized entities, like exchanges, to monitor transaction history and balances without the ability to spend funds. The master key remains necessary for spending and preserving security. Even with a view key, the observer cannot link transactions to external identities or connected addresses, ensuring privacy. Security measures include revocable keys, access logs, and selective disclosure, where users can choose which transactions or time periods to share. This system is</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On August 20th, the Salvium devs joined the Pursuit of Privacy community for an AMA. Thanks for hosting—it was a great discussion! In this AMA, we explore Salvium’s origins, its Confidential Transactions, staking model, and key innovations like Asynchronous Transactions (AT) and Transactional Imbalances (TI). We also discuss the team’s funding strategy and how Salvium aims to position itself as a leader in the privacy coin space. 1. To start the AMA, can you tell us the story behind the Salvium project, and what it aims to achieve? Salvium was originally called Fulmo as a nod to Monero (meaning ‘coin’), Fulmo means ‘lightning’ in Esperanto. The original concept was inspired by a presentation by Pedro Moreno-Sánchez at MoneroKon 2019 on “Dual Outputs: Enabling Payment-Channel Networks in Monero”. You can find it on YouTube. He highlighted the trade-offs between privacy, scalability, and functionality in cryptocurrencies and laid out a proposal using dual outputs to enable payment channels, and a lightning network style layer 2. While working through various ideas to use this extended capability set, and considering what things like conditional payments would enable, a prototype was built for a yield payment system that paid out asynchronously. Only at that point did it become clear that if you can send a transaction at one point in time, and have it do ‘stuff’ at some point in the future, then return it securely and privately—you’ve just built a system capable of running code on the blockchain. So Fulmo became too limiting a name, and Salvium was born. 2. Can you tell us about each team member’s background? Have you worked on other projects before? While we haven’t focused on individual identities, we’re not anonymous. But we are also not seeking exposure. The lead developers are known in the space as Dweab and Neac and are responsible for creating the coloured coin technology used in projects like Haven Protocol. Both are also fully doxxed, and their careers are known. Dweab started as a software engineer and mathematician and then went into high-level corporate roles. Neac has been a software engineer for over 30 years and is also a very accomplished and capable mathematician and cryptographer. Beyond these two individuals, there is a wider team of contributors that have a broad range of skills, including economics, finance, DevOps, technical, and creative. 3. You have chosen to have the project funds (12% of max supply) locked in a contract with gradual release over 24 months. Why did you choose this setup over other funding options, such as a block tax, premine, or community donations? We chose a 9% premine with a 24-month gradual release because it provides both transparency and financial stability. Another 3% was allocated to early contributors and the founding team, compensating them for nearly a year of development and costs before launch. By releasing 650,000 SAL per month, we have a stable funding source to deliver on our roadmap. We considered alternatives like community donations or ongoing developer fees, but those options either lacked financial stability or posed potential conflicts of interest. The 24-month lock-up also shows our commitment to the project’s long-term vision. In August 2024, we locked one month of unused payments for another two years to demonstrate our long-term commitment. This model allows us to focus on development without short-term market pressures. 4. People rarely discuss the choices of tokenomics and project financing (rewards/premine) over a timeline. Don’t you think your choice to allocate Salvium’s project funding with a token release over 24 months is risky given the current market conditions? It seems like a short-term bet where a bull market within the next two years is necessary to ensure your funding for the subsequent years. The timing of sales must be very well chosen to avoid running out of funding for future developments (after the first two years). What are your thoughts on this? The 24-month release was designed to meet Salvium’s initial funding needs while aligning with the community’s interests. We’re aware of the market risks, but we aren’t relying on a bull market. Our strategy includes prudent financial management, a flexible development pace that can adapt to SAL’s value, and the potential for locking additional unused SAL tokens for future use. This is to build real value and generate trust and ongoing interest. Transparency with our community is crucial throughout this process. 5. The Knowledge Base section of your website mentions that Salvium uses ‘Confidential Transactions’ to mask transaction amounts. Can you explain in detail the cryptographic mechanism used to implement these confidential transactions, and how it differs from implementations in other blockchains like Monero or Zcash? Additionally, how do you manage the verification of transaction integrity without revealing the amounts? Salvium’s Confidential Transactions (CTs) are the same as Monero’s, with the exception that Salvium also provides uniformly random commitment masks for all consumed outputs, as opposed to some consumed outputs as Monero does, creating a reduction in the potential for information leakage. 6. Staking on Salvium is based on periods of approximately 30 days (21,600 blocks) with a yield of 20% of block rewards during the initial phase of the project. How does the Salvium protocol plan to adjust these staking rewards during the transition to a fee-based DeFi model, while maintaining sufficient incentives for participants? Maintaining network security and participant incentives is a priority. The current 20% share of block rewards for stakers will remain in place as we begin rolling out DeFi features in the future. As DeFi applications grow and generate revenue, we’ll gradually transition from block reward-based staking to a gas/fee distribution model. This transition will be carefully managed, ensuring that stakers continue to receive attractive rewards. We’ll be transparent about any changes and seek community input to strike the right balance, ensuring the economic model remains sustainable as we expand DeFi capabilities. 7. Salvium introduces anonymous refundable transactions as a compliance feature. Can you detail the cryptographic process that allows for an anonymous refund of a transaction while ensuring the exact amount is returned to the correct sender? How does this mechanism integrate with other privacy features of Salvium, such as Stealth Addresses and Ring Signatures? Our approach builds upon the “Return Address Scheme” originally proposed by Knacc for Monero in 2019, adapting and extending it to meet the specific needs of Salvium’s regulatory compliance goals. We developed the mathematical proof for this in early 2024, and CypherStack audited it just before the launch of Salvium’s mainnet. Salvium’s refundable transactions are an optional feature that integrates privacy with regulatory compliance. When Alice sends a transaction to Bob, she includes an encrypted “return address” (F_ab) in the transaction, which Bob can later use if a refund is needed. This return address is encrypted using a Diffie-Hellman shared secret, ensuring only Bob can decrypt it. If a refund is required, Bob can use this information to create a new transaction without knowing Alice’s actual address. This method preserves privacy by using stealth addresses and ring signatures, maintaining unlinkability and anonymity while enabling refunds. The refund amount is verified using Pedersen commitments and range proofs, ensuring the integrity of the transaction. 8. In the Knowledge Base section, it is mentioned that exchanges require the ability to monitor transactions in authorized wallets via a ‘viewkey’ mechanism. Can you explain how this ‘view key’ mechanism is technically implemented in the Salvium protocol, and how it ensures both user privacy and regulatory compliance? What security measures are in place to prevent the abuse of these ‘view keys’ by ‘authorized entities’? The view key mechanism is currently being developed. It is being designed as an optional feature to balance privacy with compliance. Salvium will use a dual-key system: a ‘view-balance key’ (k_vb) and a ‘master key’ (k_m). The view-balance key allows authorized entities, like exchanges, to monitor transaction history and balances without the ability to spend funds. The master key remains necessary for spending and preserving security. Even with a view key, the observer cannot link transactions to external identities or connected addresses, ensuring privacy. Security measures include revocable keys, access logs, and selective disclosure, where users can choose which transactions or time periods to share. This system is]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/Blog%20AMA%20PP.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/Blog%20AMA%20PP.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Our New Desktop Wallet</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/16/desktop-wallet-launch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Our New Desktop Wallet" /><published>2024-08-16T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-16T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/16/desktop-wallet-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/16/desktop-wallet-launch/"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce the launch of our new desktop wallet, designed from the ground up to provide a seamless and secure experience for managing your digital assets. This release represents a significant milestone in our commitment to making cryptocurrency more accessible and user-friendly.</p>

<h4 id="intuitive-design--user-experience">Intuitive Design &amp; User Experience</h4>

<p>Our new wallet combines robust security features with an intuitive interface, making it easy for both newcomers and experienced users to manage their assets effectively. We’ve focused on creating a clean, straightforward design that puts the most important features at your fingertips:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Dashboard Overview</strong>: Quick access to balances and recent transactions</li>
  <li><strong>Transaction History</strong>: Detailed view of all past transactions with advanced filtering</li>
  <li><strong>Address Book</strong>: Easy management of frequently used addresses</li>
  <li><strong>Network Status</strong>: Real-time information about network health and synchronization</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="advanced-security-features">Advanced Security Features</h4>

<p>Security was our top priority during development. The wallet includes multiple layers of protection:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Encryption &amp; Key Management</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Advanced encryption for wallet files</li>
      <li>Secure key storage mechanisms</li>
      <li>Optional hardware wallet integration</li>
      <li>Multi-signature support</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Access Control</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>PIN/password protection</li>
      <li>Two-factor authentication</li>
      <li>Session management</li>
      <li>Auto-logout functionality</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Backup Solutions</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Automated backup scheduling</li>
      <li>Encrypted backup files</li>
      <li>Seed phrase recovery</li>
      <li>Cloud backup options (optional)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="core-functionality">Core Functionality</h4>

<p>The wallet supports all essential functions with enhanced features:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Transaction Management</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Fast and secure sending/receiving</li>
      <li>Custom fee settings</li>
      <li>Batch transactions</li>
      <li>Transaction notes and labels</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Address Management</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Multiple address support</li>
      <li>Address generation</li>
      <li>QR code integration</li>
      <li>Address verification</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Privacy Features</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Ring signature implementation</li>
      <li>Stealth addresses</li>
      <li>Transaction mixing</li>
      <li>Privacy level selection</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="unique-features">Unique Features</h4>

<p>We’ve implemented several unique features that set our wallet apart:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Smart Transaction Planning</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Fee optimization</li>
      <li>Transaction scheduling</li>
      <li>Recurring payments</li>
      <li>Priority management</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Integration Capabilities</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Exchange integration</li>
      <li>DeFi protocol support</li>
      <li>Cross-chain compatibility</li>
      <li>API access for developers</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="user-support--documentation">User Support &amp; Documentation</h4>

<p>We’re committed to helping users get the most out of their wallet:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>In-Wallet Help</strong>: Contextual help and tooltips</li>
  <li><strong>Documentation</strong>: Comprehensive user guides</li>
  <li><strong>Video Tutorials</strong>: Step-by-step visual guides</li>
  <li><strong>Support Chat</strong>: Direct access to support team</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="future-development">Future Development</h4>

<p>Our development roadmap includes exciting upcoming features:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Enhanced Features</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Advanced portfolio tracking</li>
      <li>Market data integration</li>
      <li>Custom alert systems</li>
      <li>Advanced analytics</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Additional Integrations</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>More hardware wallet support</li>
      <li>Additional exchange connections</li>
      <li>Enhanced DeFi capabilities</li>
      <li>Mobile companion app</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h4>

<p>Download the wallet from our official website and follow these steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Installation</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Simple setup process</li>
      <li>Quick start guide</li>
      <li>Security configuration</li>
      <li>Network synchronization</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>First Steps</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Wallet creation/import</li>
      <li>Security setup</li>
      <li>First transaction</li>
      <li>Backup creation</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>We’re committed to continuing development and improvement of the wallet based on user feedback. Regular updates will bring new features and enhancements, ensuring that our wallet remains at the forefront of cryptocurrency technology.</p>

<p>Try our new desktop wallet today and experience the future of digital asset management. For support or feedback, reach out to our team through our official channels.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the launch of our new desktop wallet, designed to provide a seamless and secure experience for managing your digital assets.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/wallet-launch.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/wallet-launch.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Salvium Treasury Update - August 2024 funds locked for 2-years</title><link href="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/15/treasury-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Salvium Treasury Update - August 2024 funds locked for 2-years" /><published>2024-08-15T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/15/treasury-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://salvium.io/blog/2024/08/15/treasury-update/"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to provide an important update regarding the Salvium Treasury management. In our ongoing commitment to transparency and long-term stability, we have implemented a significant change to our treasury holdings.</p>

<h4 id="treasury-lock-up-details"><strong>Treasury Lock-up Details</strong></h4>

<p>As of August 2024, we have:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Locked a substantial portion of treasury funds for a 2-year period</li>
  <li>Implemented smart contract-based time locks</li>
  <li>Enhanced transparency through public verification</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="strategic-benefits"><strong>Strategic Benefits</strong></h4>

<p>This decision brings several advantages to the Salvium ecosystem:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Long-term Stability</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Reduced market impact</li>
      <li>Predictable supply metrics</li>
      <li>Enhanced investor confidence</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Governance Alignment</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Clear financial planning</li>
      <li>Community-focused development</li>
      <li>Sustainable growth model</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Market Confidence</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Transparent operations</li>
      <li>Committed development</li>
      <li>Strategic resource allocation</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="verification-and-monitoring"><strong>Verification and Monitoring</strong></h4>

<p>The locked funds can be verified through:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public blockchain explorers</li>
  <li>Smart contract audits</li>
  <li>Regular treasury reports</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="looking-forward"><strong>Looking Forward</strong></h4>

<p>This treasury update represents our commitment to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sustainable development</li>
  <li>Community trust</li>
  <li>Long-term value creation</li>
</ul>

<p>We will continue to provide regular updates on treasury management and allocation strategies.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more updates on Salvium’s development and growth!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Important update on the Salvium Treasury: August 2024 funds have been locked for a 2-year period, demonstrating our long-term commitment.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/Blog%20Aug%20Tres-1024.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://salvium.io/images/blog/Blog%20Aug%20Tres-1024.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>